Today we're going to be going around
one of the wealthiest neighborhoods in Texas asking
millionaires how they became wealthy. Yeah, we're
going to be going door to door finding
out how they made their millions. Let's get to
it. All right, so we're here at our first house.
Looks beautiful. See if we can talk to the
owner and kind of figure out what they did
that's kind of led to their success and
being able to own a multimillion dollar property like
this one. So check it out. Just asking people
a couple of questions on their advice to younger
people who are coming out of college. I actually
had a phone call. Sorry, not at this time, but
no worries. All right, you guys. So next, let's
see how this goes. What industry did you decide
to pursue a career in natural gas?
The most difficult, most challenging, most dangerous
job you can find. And I proved it to a
lot of people who couldn't believe that I was doing
something like that. That's amazing. You can find
something and what else is doing work harder than
anybody else. And you're going to do just fine.
Look under the rug. If you see a problem, don't
say someone else is going to fix it. You find out
what caused it and you find out a way to fix it.
The most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year. I
don't know. Cash flow is maybe half a million dollars
a year. Wow.
No, I'm a president of a software company
that does industrial like IoT edge device management.
Right. My first job out of college was a startup.
It was a great experience because I got to learn
a lot of things and learn a lot of things the
hard way. If I had to do it again, I would have
probably first gone to work for a large company
to get exposed to kind of best practices and how
things should be done. And then going back
to a smaller company. When you start your career,
do it in a city where there are a lot of
options for you to, you know, be at one company for maybe
three or four years and move on to the other.
I think I'll pass.
All right. We have been doing some, some decent
amount of rejection so far, but the vibes are
still high. We're going to go after theợ
We're still sure that we're gonna get some good interviews.
We should keep knocking. We're going one by one.
Doesn't matter how many no's we're gonna get,
you just gotta get to that next yes.
We're back out here for day two.
Last time didn't go as planned.
Got a lot more rejections than people
that were willing to do the interviews.
So we're back out here trying to ask people, you know,
how to run up a bag and get wealthy in today's world.
I mean, it's tough, man. I don't know how many more doors
we could knock on, get no's, and the door slammed on our face.
But, you know, we're just trying
to get these answers for you guys.
So hopefully we have a better day today. Stay tuned.
So I played professional basketball for 10 years and now I'm
involved in a sports ownership group that owns teams around the world.
As an entrepreneur, what is your best piece of advice
to someone wanting to start a business going into 2023?
What I would say to anyone and what I tell my kids
and what I would tell my younger self is don't work for anyone.
Find a way to find something you're passionate about.
If you're gonna spend your time on something,
spend your time growing something that's truly yours.
And I understand that that's difficult when you're young.
But whatever you have to do, put in the effort.
Spend a few years, save as much money as you can, and then spend your time really putting
the time in to build something that you can own as opposed to being an employee for someone else.
Beautiful interview right there. Probably
my favorite one so far.
You know, he owns a basketball, a professional basketball
team in New Zealand, serial entrepreneur, professional basketball player.
Check out this court right here in his backyard, man.
It don't get any better than that.
Yeah, I had a group of like 350 radio stations.
Wow. What was the name of it?
Capstar Broadcasting.
Wow.
I bought my first station
when I was 29 years old.
So.
Wow.
What was the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Selling the company, I made
probably $50 million, something like that.
Wow.
So that's good.
That's incredible.
Good year.
What advice would you tell someone
wanting to start a business in 2023?
You know, I think it's really about people you're connected to, learning how to communicate and build
a great team of people, trusting them and having a good business plan and going for it.
And what do you look for in, you know, various other employees or
business partners that tells you, hey, this is someone I want to work with?
Actually, I look for somebody who's had some failure.
You learn more about the character of a person once they've fallen on their
face and gotten back up and seeing what kind of business person they really are.
How's today been so far?
You know, not too bad.
It's been a little slow.
You know, it's kind of funny.
One of the first houses we went up to, a lady had came out and after we gave her
our pitch to do an interview, she kind of goes, it's kind of weird what you guys are doing.
And to be honest, you know, it is a little insane that we're
just going door to door in some of these like really nice neighborhoods.
People are probably really caught off guard.
They've probably never seen or kind
of experienced something like it before.
So.
It does make sense.
But yeah, just been trying to
drive around, scout up these homes.
I mean, we've been hitting every little pocket in Austin.
It's got these nice homes
and Austin's got plenty of them.
We just got to get out more, maybe go across the other
side of the city to try to find some more million dollar homes.
I was lucky enough to become a trial lawyer.
It's what I always wanted to
be since I was in eighth grade.
So I get to play with other
people's money, which is pretty darn nice.
I used to own part of three bars in Houston.
What would be your best piece of
advice to entrepreneurs going into next year?
Do your homework.
You know, I see businesses
open in Austin all the time.
And I'm like, I'm going to do this.
I'm going to do this.
And I'm kind of wondering, did
anybody study the demographics of that location?
We just got a new pizza parlor in
Westlake and I was very excited about it.
And then I went over
there and discovered they sold slices.
Slices.
Well, that's great if you're in Times Square, but there's not
enough foot traffic over by Randall's supermarket in Westlake to sell slices.
So I kind of wondered to myself, who
did their homework before they opened this business?
These videos, especially this one in particular, is actually really hard
to film because our success rate is easily less than 5%.
Most people don't even answer the door and the people that do answer
the door, it's a toss up if they're willing to do the interview.
So if you guys did enjoy this video
so far, please leave a like and subscribe.
I would really appreciate that from you guys.
Did you ever own a
company at any point in time?
Yes, I was CEO and founder of two technical companies.
MRI Systems, it was acquired by
Intel and one is called MyVest.
It's in San Francisco.
It was acquired by TIAA.
What's your best piece of advice to someone wanting
to start a business going into this next year?
Learn a lot.
Get a marketable skill and master it.
What do you typically look for in a company that tells you, hey, I want to
invest in this company and when do you know when it's a good time to buy?
You know, timing is difficult, but generally you
have to have a long term investment horizon.
So you have to be willing to put some
money away that you won't need for maybe ten years.
What's the most amount of money that
you've ever made in a single year?
It's in the seven digits.
I'd rather not get too specific about that.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
IT.
I studied at UT.
And what were you doing before being a professor?
I was a software engineer for ten years and I
was a stay at home dad for five or ten years.
What was the best financial decision that you ever made?
I guess investing in real estate
long term was a good decision.
Also, marry a successful lawyer.
That's a really good advice.
OK.
If you can do that, you're more than halfway there.
In what industry did you ultimately pursue a career in?
I was in sales.
What do you think really separates people
when they're in sales competing against other people?
Persistence.
And just keeping going and being relentless.
If something isn't working, you know,
reevaluate and be willing to change.
Don't be stubborn about it.
But also just power through
because sometimes it's just really hard.
I created a real estate development company
here in Austin, Texas that's pretty successful.
What is something that you've done among your competitors to really make you stand
out and that you think other people should try and implement regardless of the industry?
Know what you're going after, know your market and be
able to make fast decisions and have conviction about them.
What's the greatest lesson that you've learned through your career
in real estate that you would want to tell someone else?
There's just opportunity in all
the different areas within real estate.
If you want to cut
lawn, you could be successful there.
If you want to, you know,
buy and sell properties, buy land.
I mean, there's so many opportunities.
It's just finding what you know and what you want to do and just doing it and
working fast, having conviction, keeping a good name and good reputation and, you know, treat your investors properly.
How can someone start their
path to becoming wealthy in 2023?
So going back to when I was younger,
and I can just go from personal experience.
You can always find a
way to put your money in.
Put money aside.
And the way that I was able to break off and frankly, when we
started the brokerage career, I started, you know, on my own with a partner.
But the two of us were really young and I
had enough savings that I was able to make that commitment.
You know, without that savings, I would
have never been able to have that choice.
I feel like a lot of people going out to eat
or going on vacations, and I know that's part of life.
But without financial stability, you lose optionality.
So I think that's the way I would go.
Thank you guys so much for tuning in to today's video
and stay tuned for tons of amazing content on the way.
We spent the last few days asking multimillionaires their advice on how
they became rich and how you can become successful in today's world.